<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>My Blog on FLUKA</title>
    <link>https://Mehdibenabdelkader.github.io/Flukadev/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in My Blog on FLUKA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 14:46:47 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Mehdibenabdelkader.github.io/Flukadev/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Today I Learned : Monolith vs Microservices</title>
      <link>https://Mehdibenabdelkader.github.io/Flukadev/blog/tilmonolithvsmicroservices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 17:33:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Mehdibenabdelkader.github.io/Flukadev/blog/tilmonolithvsmicroservices/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;There are only two ways to lead: you either divide and conquer, or you build and unite.&amp;rdquo;
This concept of dividing to conquer was a staple in the course of my academic life, I found it very intresting how such an idea can be applied to multiple fields of study, even in life problems. And on my journey towards becoming a better devops enginner, I learned that this concept is the base of a whole architecture, and the difference between monolithic applications and microservices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From UI/UX Design to Devops : A leap of faith</title>
      <link>https://Mehdibenabdelkader.github.io/Flukadev/blog/fromuiuxtodevops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 16:10:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Mehdibenabdelkader.github.io/Flukadev/blog/fromuiuxtodevops/</guid>
      <description>My Journey: Transitioning from UI/UX Design to DevOps Engineering Introduction Life often presents us with unexpected opportunities for growth and change. It pushes you into paths you never thought you&amp;rsquo;d walk in, and my path took from being a seasoned UI/UX designer to becoming a aspiring and pationate DevOps engineer, it&amp;rsquo;s a chance for bothseeking fresh challenges, exploring new horizons and pushing my limits. In this blog post, I&amp;rsquo;ll share my story of why I decided to make this career switch, the surprising similarities I found between the two fields, and the hurdles I had and still have to overcome to become the best at what I do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the tools: Why Understanding UI Design Theory Matters</title>
      <link>https://Mehdibenabdelkader.github.io/Flukadev/blog/uitoolsvstheory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 09:50:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Mehdibenabdelkader.github.io/Flukadev/blog/uitoolsvstheory/</guid>
      <description>Lately I received many questions concerning Ui design and got to speak to many people about the topic, and that&amp;rsquo;s due to User Interface (UI) design playing a pivotal role in creating engaging, user-friendly experiences across various platforms and devices. And the pattern I always notice is the temptation to dive straight into learning the latest design tools and software, neglecting the importance of understanding UI design theory which can be a more strategic and enduring approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UX Insights from a Wedding</title>
      <link>https://Mehdibenabdelkader.github.io/Flukadev/blog/uxtipsfromawedding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 23:49:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Mehdibenabdelkader.github.io/Flukadev/blog/uxtipsfromawedding/</guid>
      <description>As someone who draws inspiration from the real world, I find myself constantly observing life&amp;rsquo;s intricacies. I&amp;rsquo;m on a quest to become a better UI/UX Designer, a more diligent student, and a more compassionate human being in general. Yesterday I had the pleasure of attending a wedding – a celebration brimming with delectable food, enchanting music, and countless lessons waiting to be learned.
Research is Crucial: The Surprising Fashion Fiasco The morning of the wedding dawned, and I was brimming with excitement, ready to unveil my carefully chosen outfit: sleek black pants paired with a crisply ironed white shirt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Story Behind My First Blog</title>
      <link>https://Mehdibenabdelkader.github.io/Flukadev/blog/myfirstblogpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 02:38:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Mehdibenabdelkader.github.io/Flukadev/blog/myfirstblogpost/</guid>
      <description>In the vast digital landscape of the internet, where humanity&amp;rsquo;s thoughts, ideas, and experiences converge, there&amp;rsquo;s something truly magical about carving out your own little corner to share your voice, even though it might appear as another droplet in the a never ending digital sea. Writing a blog is far more than just slapping words on a screen; it&amp;rsquo;s about embracing creativity, the itch to connect and the desire to share with others.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
